<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mdRecord xmlns="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
    xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
    xmlns:edm="http://www.europeana.eu/schemas/edm/"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu
dplava.xsd">
    <dcterms:identifier>TAU_ART_000123</dcterms:identifier>
    <dcterms:title>Portrait of Norah Gribble</dcterms:title>
    <dcterms:description>This evocative piece by Sargent, one of the greatest portrait artists in
        American history, is among his largest full-length portraits. He won praise and critical
        acclaim for his looser approach to brushstrokes and ability to to reveal the psychology of
        his sitters. Sargent's Paris studio flourished in the late 1880s until he exhibited the
        scandalous and widely criticized portrait Madame X, a work he later sold for £1,000 to the
        Metropolitan Museum of Art in 1916. The tumult drove him out of France and into Britain,
        where he established a prosperous studio as a portrait painter for wealthy, elite patrons
        from England and the United States. The portrait of Norah Gribble (a London based socialite
        in her early 20s) is particularly notable for its massive scale, lifelike quality, and her
        alluring glance at the viewer. During Sargent's career, he painted some 900 oil paintings
        and more than 2,000 sketches and charcoal drawings.</dcterms:description>
    <dcterms:description>Second picture: Detail showing evidence, in the shine of the varnish, of
        the original frontal pose</dcterms:description>
    <dcterms:creator>John Singer Sargent (American, 1856-1925)</dcterms:creator>
    <dcterms:subject>Virginia</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Art</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:created>1888</dcterms:created>
    <dcterms:type>Image</dcterms:type>
    <dcterms:isPartOf>Taubman Museum of Art</dcterms:isPartOf>
    <dcterms:medium>painting (visual works)</dcterms:medium>
    <dcterms:medium>oil on canvas</dcterms:medium>
    <dcterms:format>image/jpeg</dcterms:format>
    <dcterms:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC-EDU/1.0/</dcterms:rights>
    <dcterms:provenance>Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University. University
        Libraries</dcterms:provenance>
    <edm:isShownAt>https://di.lib.vt.edu/items/show/947</edm:isShownAt>
    <edm:preview>https://di.lib.vt.edu/files/thumbnails/14/TAU_ART_000123/TAU_ART_000123_0002.jpg</edm:preview>
</mdRecord>
