<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mdRecord xmlns="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
    xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
    xmlns:edm="http://www.europeana.eu/schemas/edm/"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu
dplava.xsd">
    <dcterms:identifier>TAU_ART_000113 2002.004</dcterms:identifier>
    <dcterms:title>Voyage of the Polaris</dcterms:title>
    <dcterms:description>Maritime painter William Bedford was well known for his ship portraiture
        that employ painstaking precision, clarity and preoccupation with light. Intrigued with the
        challenge of new artistic frontiers through scientific exploration, he traveled to the New
        England and Canadian shores and further north into the Arctic area of the Labrador coast.
        Voyage of the Polaris depicts the 1871 ill-fated arctic exploration vessel icebound in the
        frozen sea of Thank-God Harbor off the coast of Greenland. En route to its final
        destination, Captain Francis Hall died mysteriously and it was speculated that the ship's
        doctor murdered him. Shortly thereafter, Polaris struck an iceberg. Bradford's painting
        depicts a desperate moment of action: the 34-man crew quickly off-loading provisions to
        lighten the ship's weight, but their efforts were unsuccessful. although the crew watched
        from the frozen tundra as the ship capsized, all members were eventually rescued. Although
        Bradford did not have direct experience with Polaris, he was familiar with the voyage from
        published accounts of its expedition.</dcterms:description>
    <dcterms:creator>William Bradford (American, 1823-1892)</dcterms:creator>
    <dcterms:subject>Virginia</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:subject>Art</dcterms:subject>
    <dcterms:created>1875</dcterms:created>
    <dcterms:type>Image</dcterms:type>
    <dcterms:isPartOf>Taubman Museum of Art</dcterms:isPartOf>
    <dcterms:medium>painting (visual works)</dcterms:medium>
    <dcterms:medium>oil</dcterms:medium>
    <dcterms:format>image/jpeg</dcterms:format>
    <dcterms:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC-EDU/1.0/</dcterms:rights>
    <dcterms:provenance>Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University. University
        Libraries</dcterms:provenance>
    <edm:isShownAt>https://di.lib.vt.edu/items/show/938</edm:isShownAt>
    <edm:preview>http://di.lib.vt.edu/files/thumbnails/14/TAU_ART_000113 2002.004/TAU_ART_000113
        2002.004.jpg</edm:preview>
</mdRecord>
